{
    "id": "8b2f0f8ec3314f05815655dfdbf46d66",
    "title": "Gerunds And Participles",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "ce6bbf5f0b7147e19540627c9f767640",
            "title": "Gerunds And Participles",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "He is fond …………………….. cricket.",
                    "description": "Certain adjectives are followed by ‘preposition + ing form’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to play",
                        "of playing",
                        "of to play"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "………………………… along the road, he found a dead cobra.",
                    "description": "When we split the clauses we get: \r\nHe was walking along the road\r\nHe found a dead cobra.\r\nWe can connect them with the present participle ‘walking’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Walking",
                        "To walk",
                        "Having walked"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We were prevented …………………………. the patient.",
                    "description": "The verb prevent is followed by 'preposition + ing form’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to see",
                        "from seeing",
                        "to seeing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I hope you will excuse …………………………… leaving early.",
                    "description": "The word leaving is a gerund that serves the same purpose as a noun. We cannot use an object pronoun to modify a noun instead we use a possessive adjective (my).",
                    "answers": [
                        "me",
                        "my",
                        "I"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We rejoiced at ………………………….. being promoted.",
                    "description": "The word being is a gerund that serves the same purpose as a noun. We cannot use an object pronoun to modify a noun instead we use a possessive adjective (his).",
                    "answers": [
                        "him",
                        "he",
                        "his"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I insist on ………………………… being present at the meeting.",
                    "description": "The word being is a gerund that serves the same purpose as a noun. We cannot use an object pronoun to modify a noun instead we use a possessive adjective (your).",
                    "answers": [
                        "you",
                        "your",
                        "yours"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We left without ……………………….. knowing.",
                    "description": "The word knowing is a gerund that serves the same purpose as a noun. We use a possessive expression to modify a noun. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "anyone",
                        "anyone's",
                        "anyones"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "All depends on ………………………… passing the exam.",
                    "description": "The word passing is a gerund that serves the same purpose as a noun. We use a possessive expression to modify a noun. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "John",
                        "John's"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It ……………………… a very hot day, I remained in my tent.",
                    "description": "It was a very hot day. I remained in my tent. We can combine them with the participle being.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was",
                        "being",
                        "been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………………………… across the heath, a gipsy found the child.",
                    "description": "A gypsy was wandering across the heath. He found the child. \r\nWe can combine them with the present participle wandering.\r\n",
                    "answers": [
                        "Wandered",
                        "Wandering",
                        "Having wandered"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………………………….. his lesson, he went out to play.",
                    "description": "He had learned his lesson. He went out to play. We can combine them with the perfect participle ‘having learned’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Learning",
                        "Learned",
                        "Having learned"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We met an old man …………………………….. to Jerusalem.",
                    "description": "We met an old man. He was walking to Jerusalem.\r\nWe can combine the two clauses with the present participle ‘walking’.\r\n",
                    "answers": [
                        "walking",
                        "walked"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}